Mss.Rec.68 Mss.Rec.68
American Philosophical Society
Materials Recorded at Copper Center, Alaska
1968-1969
Mss.Rec.68
American Philosophical Society
27.0 Reel(s)
Ahtna songs and stories recorded at Copper Center, Alaska in 1968 by Frederica de Laguna. Includes dance songs, sorry songs, potlatch songs, sleep doctor songs, and others. Includes "Gulkana Potlatch Given by Bill Joe and Kate Sanford for Recovery of Maggie Joe from Illness." Some songs are Tlingit, Upper Tanana, or Tanacross in origin. Also includes Ahtna stories, autobiographical accounts, vocabularies, and interviews.
27 sound tape reels (14 hr., 55 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in. and 7 in.
De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
Note on numbering
Tapes are numbered 1-28, with no tape 18.
Conditions Governing Access
Permission required for access to materials. Please consult the Manuscripts Librarian for details.
Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Folklore; Indians of North America--Alaska--Languages; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Interviews.; Songs.; Vocabularies.
- Audio recordings
  - Gulkana Potlatch Given by Bill Joe and Kate Sanford for Recovery of Maggie Joe from Illness
    - Short snatch of Northway song, 1968-06-16; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
      Existence and Location of Originals note
      This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
      Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Gulkana (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Potlatch--Alaska
    - Northern song, 1968-06-16; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:18; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Northern song, 1968-06-16; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Ahtna song, 1968-06-16; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - TcElali [drinking song], from Up-the-Line, 1968-06-16; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:53; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Dance Song, 1968-06-16; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-06-16; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-06-16; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Andrew Isaac's Sorry Song for Johnny Frank [Johnson?], c. 1966, 1968-06-16; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Lucy Adams' Sorry Song for her Son, Tetlin, 1968-06-16; 01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Andrew David's or Walter David's Sorry Song for their Father, Chief David of Tetlin, 1968-06-16; 01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Big Mark's Sorry Song for his Son, Tanacross, 1968-06-16; 01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Mrs. Banzanita Billy's Sorry Song for her Son, 1968-06-16; 01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Tanacross Song, 1968-06-16; 01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-06-16; 01-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Kitty David's Tanana Boat Song, Tetlin (not completed), 1968-06-16; 01-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Dance Song, 1968-06-16; 01-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-06-16; 01-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Traditional First Song by Potlatch Guests (Up-the-Line), 1968-06-16; 01-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Buster Jim's Dance Song, Northway, 1968-06-16; 01-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Dance Song, "Something Follow Me", 1968-06-16; 01-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Down-below Song, call for supper (?), 1968-06-16; 01-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    - Identification of recording, 1968; 01-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:17; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
      Scope and Contents note
      Identification of the occasion of the recording of previously recorded songs (APSdigrec_1349 - APSdigrec_1370).
  - Interview with Jenny Peters, 1968-06-25; 01-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Peters, Jenny
    In English with occasional Ahtena vocabulary. Continued on next tape. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians; Ahtena language; Cantwell (Alaska)
  - Interview with Jenny Peters, Jake & Lily Tanzy, 1968-06-25; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:26; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Peters, Jenny; Tanzy, Jake; Tanzy, Lily
    Includes discussion of Ahtena vocabulary. Continuation of interview conducted with Jenny Peters in her home. For beginning section, see Related Recording item #1. Includes a rendition of Big Mark's Sorry Song for his son. For another version, see Related Recording item #2. In English with occasional Ahtena vocabulary.
    Ahtena Indians; Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Cantwell (Alaska); Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Vocabulary from Tenas Charley, 1968-06-29; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:48; Charley, Tenas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Ahtena Indians--Ethnobiology; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Interview with Arthur Jackson, 1968-06-30; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:58; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur
    Arthur Jackson tells about his first meeting with white men in 1898 and about his first hunt.
    Ahtena Indians--First contact with Europeans; Ahtena Indians--History; Ahtena Indians--Hunting; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Hunting--Alaska
  - Glacier Man's Song to Stop Rain, 1968-06-30; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Incorrectly identified on the recording as a Groundsquirrel Song.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Woman's song: "You're going to see them again." by Martha, 1968-06-30; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    An Up-the-Line song. Song was prompted by a Sarani Song recorded in 1954. See Related Recording.
  - Tlingit Worry Song, 1968-06-30; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Song was prompted by Tlingit Worry Song recorded in 1954. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tlingit language
  - Sorry song by a woman who killed her brother for incest, 1968-06-30; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Andrew Isaac's sorry song for Johnny Frank, 1968-06-30; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    An Up-the-Line song. Ends with identification of this recording and previously recorded material from the same session (APSdigrec_1374 - APSdigrec_1380).
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tanacross language
  - Tenas Waski song, 1968-07-19; 04-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit dance song (ya 'eli ya) with drum, 1968-07-19; 04-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - A different Tlingit song, 1968-07-19; 04-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Jim McKinley's Sorry Song for Oscar Craig (1967), 1968-07-19; 04-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Martha records sounds of different loons, 1968-07-19; 04-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:39; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Birdsongs--Alaska; Copper Center (Alaska); Loons--Folklore
  - Bacille records traditional ending of myths, 1968-07-19; 04-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Snatch of Sleep Doctor's song about YAngRadi sARani, 1968-07-19; 04-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Shamanism--Alaska
  - Bacille George's Grandma's Love Song, 1968-07-19; 04-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:05; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs
  - Sorry Song by SaRatlE, NAltsina, 1968-07-19; 04-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Lucy Adam's Sorry Song for her Son, Tetlin, 1968-07-19; 04-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Upper Tanana language
  - Part of Sorry Song for Lucy Adam's son, 1968-07-19; 04-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:24; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Martha Jackson recites Hoijer's Word list, with additions [1 of 2], 1968-07-13; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:58; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976; Jackson, Martha
    The word list used in the recording was compiled by Harry Hoijer.
    Ahtena language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Two songs by Martha Jackson, 1968-07-04; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Hunting songs
  - Camp Robber (Canada Jay)'s song, when one is going to kill a moose, 1968-07-04; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Hunting songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Moose hunting
  - Martha tells story of her life, 1968-07-12; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Interview includes 6 shaman's songs.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Shamanism--Alaska
  - Martha Jackson recites Hoijer's Word list, with additions [2 of 2], 1968-07-13; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976; Jackson, Martha
  - Rerecording of Frank Charley's Song for Sanford Charley, 1968-07-13; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    A version of Frank Charley's Sorry Song for Sanford Charley, recorded in 1960, is played while Martha Jackson sings with the tape. For 1960 recording of song, see Related Recording item 1. For transcription of words, see Related Recording item 2.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Elizabeth imitates crooning to a baby; deL imitates baby's cries, 1968-07-15; 07-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Pete, Elizabeth
    Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Infants--Care
  - Martha dictates the words to Frank Charley's song, 1968-07-31; 07-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Dictation in Ahtena of words to Frank Charley's Song for Sanford Charley, recorded earlier on the same tape. See Related Recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Victory Song for Cantwell-Valdez Creek War, 1968-07-31; 07-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); War songs
  - Victory Song "Stinking" for Cantwell-Valdez Creek War, 1968-07-31; 07-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Interview and songs with Andy Brown, 1968-07-20; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:22; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    An interview in which several songs are sung and explained.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Eyak language; Tlingit language
  - Kate Sanford's song for her sister, Maggie Joe, when the latter was sick, 1968-07-21; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Frank Charley's Sorry Song for his older brother, 1968-07-21; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Fred Ewan's Sorry Song for his Uncle, 1968-07-21; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Mrs. Banzanita Billy's phonograph Sorry Song for her Son, 1968-07-21; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Tcelali Drinking Song, 1968-07-21; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Drinking songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Long Lucy sings snatches, 1968-07-21; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy
    Consists of four or five short sections of songs said to be of Lucy John's own composition.
  - Kodiak Song, from Eklutna, 1968-07-21; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Dena'ina language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Kodiak Song, brought by TAltsina, 1968-07-21; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Jim P. Sinyone tells story about TAltsina origins, 1968-07-21; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sinyone, Jim
    Chistochina (Alaska); Dena'ina Indians; Dena'ina Indians--Folklore
  - Tanana Crossing Good-By Song, 1968-07-21; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language
  - Banzanita Billy's Love Song, 1968-07-21; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs
  - NAlbei, You're not my Sweetheart, 1968-07-21; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Gene Nicolai's Love Song for his Run-away Wife, 1968-07-21; 09-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Chitina Teasing Song, 1968-07-21; 09-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Chief Andrew's Love Song, 1968-07-21; 09-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Song is repeated to capture to the beginning of the song, which is missed on the first run-through.
  - Tlingit Song, 1968-07-21; 09-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Copper River Dance Song, 1968-07-21; 09-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena dance; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Tenas Waski song, from Juneau, 1968-07-21; 09-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Bear Spearing Dance Song, 1968-07-21; 09-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Hunting songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Song of Crow and Seagull Eating, 1968-07-21; 09-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:30; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - "Stinking" Victory Song and explanation, 1968-07-21; 09-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; War songs
  - Tanana Boat Song, 1968-07-21; 09-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Identification of recording, 1968-07-21; 09-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Identification at end of tape of prior songs recorded on that tape. (APSdigrec_1403 - APSdigrec_1424)
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Upper Tanana vocabulary, 1968-07-24; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:58; David, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    This vocabulary was collected by Paul & Trude A. Milanowski in Tetlin in 1961. The vocabulary was read by Jessie David, assisted by other unidentified Tetlin residents. Occasionally a Tanacross pronunciation is given.
    Tanacross language; Tetlin (Alaska); Upper Tanana language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.
  - Sorry Song Composed by Bernice Joe for her father, Frank Titus, 1968-07-25; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Song was composed in 1959 or 1960.
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tanana Indians--Music; Tetlin (Alaska); Upper Tanana language
  - David Northway's Song, 1968-07-25; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanana Indians--Music; Tetlin (Alaska); Upper Tanana language
  - Andrew Isaac's sorry song for his son, 1968-07-25; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Song was composed at Tanacross in 1966 or 1967.
  - David Northway's dance song, 1968-07-25; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:43; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Song consists mostly of drumming.
  - Dance Song from Minto, 1968-07-25; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanana Indians--Music; Tanana language; Tetlin (Alaska)
  - David Teagle's sorry song for his father, 1968-07-25; 11-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tanacross language; Tanana Indians--Music; Tetlin (Alaska)
  - Big Mark's Sorry Song for his son, 1968-07-25; 11-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Composed by Big Mark of Tanacross, who died in 1905. "He start to die. Next morning get up. He chase that silver fox. See that silver fox track. [The tracks remind him of his dead son.]"
  - Paul Joe's Song, 1968-07-25; 11-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
  - Annie Joe's Sorry Song, 1968-07-25; 11-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Issac, Andrew; Joe, Annie; Joe, Bernice; Joe, Paul; Northway, David; Teagle, David
    Song is played twice. Words are the same as "Andrew Isaac's sorry song for his son." May be the same song. See Related Recording.
  - Identification of recording, 1968-07-25; 11-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Identification of previous items on reel. (APSdigrec_1427, APSdigrec_1737 - APSdigrec_1744)
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanana Indians--Music; Tetlin (Alaska)
  - Kitty David's Song, 1968-07-26; 11-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Tanana Boat Song, first attempt, 1968-07-26; 11-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Adam, Alfred; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Tanana Boat Song, 1968-07-26; 11-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; Adam, Alfred; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Annie Joe's Song, 1968-07-26; 11-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Annie
  - Lucy Adam's father's song when his daughter died in 1918, 1968-07-26; 11-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:48; Adam, Alfred; Adam, Lucy; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Jimmy Paul's grandpa's song for death of Lucy Adam's sister, 1918, 1968-07-26; 11-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; Adam, Lucy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Lucy's daddy's song for Adam's son, 1968-07-26; 11-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:42; Adam, Alfred; Adam, Lucy; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Lucy Adam's Mother's Song for her sister, 1968-07-26; 11-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Adam, Alfred; Adam, Lucy; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Lucy Adam's own song for her father, 1968-07-26; 11-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Adam, Alfred; Adam, Lucy; David, Kitty; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Johnny Goodlataw's Sleep Doctor Song about Bush Indians, 1968-07-31; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Big Stickwan's Sleep Doctor Song: "Different People Give It", 1968-07-31; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Eskaldita's Sleep Doctor Song (no words), 1968-07-31; 12-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Shamanism--Alaska